(757) 374 0095 · emilygmacon@gmail.com San Francisco, CA · www.EmilyMacon.com

EMILY MACON

I am a visual designer who has brought brands to life, built front-end websites, and led teams across design and engineering. Visually, I'm an expert letterer, illustrator, bezier wrangler, and colorist. Cognitively, I'm a detail-oriented project manager, working fast without sacrificing quality, attention to detail, or losing sight of the broader goal. While I'm proud of my design eye, my most valuable quality is the ability to (successfully) implement any project thrown at me from conception to completion.

I am currently an independent designer leading visual and product design for Eliqs, and contracting out several other projects for a wide array of clients ranging from new podcasts to NFL players. Prior, I led design for two years at a stealth sports robotics startup where I translated complex data and concepts into digestible visualizations across all user touches from company branding to the app, website, and beyond. I also recently graduated from Cooper Union's intensive one-year program where I honed in my craft of lettering and created two complete typefaces. Outside of work, I'm an artist primarily working with oil paints on a large scale.

EXPERIENCE

EMI ART & DESIGN LLC

Contract Visual Designer ♦ San Francisco ♦ Feb 2016 - Present Projects ranging from lettering & illustration to web & product design

- Lead designer for Eliqs (contract) responsible for logo design & branding, illustrations, >40 custom can designs, all marketing collateral, and communications with both client and supply side partners
- Logos and branding for several clients including Falling in Love with Leah Lamarr podcast, Peyton Barber, Noh Leftovers, Vitabox, and other Bay Area startups
- · Web design and implementation for Humboldt Legends
- · Email templates, product site pages, and pitch deck for Feastly

ICUEMOTION

Lead Visual Designer ♦ San Francisco ♦ May 2016 – Dec 2018 Lead Designer under top robotics engineer Bérénice Mettler, Ph.D.

- Developed CueMate's visual language, including custom illustrations, animations, and brand guidelines
- Designed + coded website for CueMate products and iCueMotion R&D Lab
- Designed app UX/UI for iPhone, iPad, and Apple Watch; managed team of engineers for implementation
- Managed beta cohort validating technology and testing UX/UI

MARKETBRIDGE

Designer, **Consultant** ♦ San Francisco, Washington DC ♦ July 2013 – Nov 2015 I started at the boutique consulting firm as a Consultant. After clear interest in design, I was promoted to a custom Design role focusing on data visualization.

- Designed training tools for Saks Fifth Avenue associates to pitch SaksFirst credit cards to customers; these tools doubled credit card activation within the first year
- Designed all infographics for Humana marketing campaign that
 contributed to 3x active user base; managed Humana's 3-person web development
 team, 13 copy writers, and 4 partners and redesigned the site UX, increasing both
 article page views and time on page by 20%
- Developed Microsoft's successful lead scoring model based on firmographic & behavioral data
- Designed >100 client-facing decks and misc. projects for clients such as PayPal, Cisco, Neiman Marcus, HP, and Dell

SKILLS AND TOOLS

- Adobe Illustrator for icons and general vector graphic design
- Adobe Photoshop for image editing and simple animation
- Adobe InDesign for books and zines
- Adobe Animate for complex animation
- Sketch for web and app design
- Invision for rapid prototyping
- Procreate for illustration and lettering sketches
- Robofont for typeface development and instances benefiting from more control over Bezier curves. For more meticulous type development, I also use Superpolator, and MetricsMachine.
- Extremely proficient in HTML and CSS and can navigate JS and React; track changes with Git

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA McIntire School of Commerce, College of Arts & Sciences GPA: 3.92/4.0, Dean's List all semes

GPA: 3.92/4.0, Dean's List all semesters, Graduated with High Distinction

Double Major:

BS Commerce, BA Studio Art

TYPE@COOPER WEST EXTENDED PROGRAM (COOPER UNION)

Student, 2017-18

Comprehensive study of key typeface design principles: techniques, technology, expression, history, & theory

Created two full character type families: Ionic Rebellion & Ghent

HOBBIES

- Hand and vector lettering
- Identifying typefaces in the wild
- Illustration and figure drawing
- Large-scale oil portrait commissions
- Creating custom jewelry
- Making and eating sushi
- Language of flowers & collecting plants